Thomas Miller

Frontend Web Developer

thomas.miller147@gmail.com

0 1630 Bulle, Switzerland

github.com/Meuss





+41 79 560 20 71

01.09.1987



Swiss nationality

[4 thomasmiller.ch



Internet enthousiast, I have been building websites since 2013. Bilingual French-English and self-taught mostly thanks to online tutorials, I am constantly improving my knowledge and I fully commit to my projects, looking to be proud of what I build. My goal is to continue gain more expertise in the frontend world by working on interesting projects, both visually and functionality-wise.

Education

2010 - 2014

Bachelor of Arts in Information Systems

University of Fribourg

2003 - 2008

Maturité fédérale

Collège du Sud, Bulle

Language skills Bilingual French/English

German: good knowledge Spanish: basic knowledge

Online resources

Podcast fanatic, frontendmasters, Wes Bos, Level Up Tuts, Udemy and many others.

Professional experience

Dec 2019 - Today

Freelancing

I've been building and maintaining web projects as a freelancer, until I find my next new job position.

Sept - Nov 2019

Frontend dev / WordPress @ CDI digital, Fribourg

I worked together with .NET developers on the frontend side of projects: WordPress, legacy projects Sitefinity + Telerik, an ecommerce Kindle website and a Vue.js project.

2015 - 2019

Web dev @ macmac SA, Marly

I learned a lot about how to build websites, from start to finish. Our projects were mainly visually pleasing websites built around a CMS, or SPAs with JS frameworks (Vue.js).

I learned a lot about layouts, tech stack choices, animations, interactivity, ecommerce, all while keeping an eye on performance, crossbrowser issues and SEO. I worked closely with the designer, the clients and other developers on many very different projects.

Coding











Javascript (ES6+) HTML / CSS PHP Animations Git

> Crossbrowser Responsive

Tools







Vue.js Nuxt.js Greensock jQuery npm Webpack

Gulp

CMS







WordPress Kirbv Prismic Woocommerce Shopify

Design





Sketch Photoshop Webflow